John "Boots" Highland

Principal Front-End UI/UX Engineer



Seasoned UI/UX engineer/web developer of 25 years, with 7 years experience developing and managing Shopify eCommerce websites. Specializing in modern, accessible, and performant layouts. Uniquely approaching web development from a creative, design perspective. Known for bulletproof code that works cross-browser, and is fully-responsive for all device sizes and types. Recognized for collaborating cross-functionally to maintain industry best practices, techniques and brand quidelines. Methodical with client relationships and technical assessments. Inquisitive, organized, with exceptional attention to detail.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Senior Manager of Web Development / Principal UI Engineer SEP 2018 -JAN 2023 Mizzen+Main • Dallas, TX

Handled front-end development. Managed day-to-day running of website (Shopify). Ensured site updates aligned with strict branding **standards**. Worked cross-functionally to ideate, plan, and develop site updates and online projects. Managed team of back-end and junior developers. Represented eCommerce team as part of company-wide leadership. Boldly strived to uphold and promote company's established values.

- → Successfully led planning and transition of old Shopify Liquid online store to new **React/Next.js/Shopify/**"headless" **CMS** environment in less than 6 months. Massive improvement in speed and performance contributed to company's largest annual revenue, beating previous Black Friday/Cyber Monday single-day sales records by 40%.
- Overhauled datalayer and tracking events, and worked with 3rd-party partners to optimize/streamline GTM tags. Installed custom Heap integration, resulting in more robust tracking of customer behavior, facilitating more effective marketing ad spend.

Senior Web Developer NOV 2015 -**SEP 2018**

Good Work • Dallas, TX

Developed award-winning client websites from start to finish using designs supplied by in-house designers. Primarily developed with **CraftCMS**, along with some **custom Shopify sites**. Built custom content management interface for each client. Skilled in managing multiple site builds simultaneously.

→ Built massive new content-managed site for the Gladney Center for Adoption (adoptionsbygladney.com), one of nation's largest adoption agencies. Ideated and executed "Find a Family" registry for expecting mothers to find best-matched adoptive families. Site won 2016 DSVC Bronze Award. Client reported significant increase in interest for adoption services following rollout of new branding/website.

PERSONAL INFO

Seattle, WA

469-878-0490

hello@boots.media

linkedin.com/in/boots-highland

SAMPLES OF WORK

Websites can be fleeting, so much of my previous work is no longer available online. Fortunately, you can find video walkthroughs, screenshots, and some links at my website:

www.boots.dev

PRIMARY SKILLS

Front-End Development

Semantic/Accessible HTML

Modern/Responsive CSS

SASS

JavaScript

React/Next.is

TypeScript

Liquid Templating

PHP

MySQL

Shopify Website Management

CraftCMS

Twig Templating

CMS Planning/Design

Adobe Photoshop

Adobe Illustrator

Figma

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (cont.)

John "Boots" Highland (cont.)

Senior Web Developer SEP 2011 -NOV 2015

Switch • Dallas, TX

Developed and managed wide range of client websites - start to finish - including major restaurant chains, banks and financial services firms, and large B2C retail stores. Primarily developed using ExpressionEngine, and a few custom WordPress themes. Built custom content management interface for each client. Able to manage multiple simultaneous site builds. Won multiple DSVC and AIGA awards.

Web/Flash Developer DEC 2004 -**SEP 2011**

AM Design (currently AM Agency) • N Richland Hills, TX

Specialized in large-scale Flash websites for large clients, including major retail chains, major Christian ministries, and mega-churches across the country.

- → Built large-scale, immersive Flash experience websites for the annual Passion Conferences, an international series of conferences for Christian youth.
- → Built elaborate Flash experiences for major retail companies to promote various internal and external events and promotions. Clients included AT&T, Sonic Drive-Ins, Dr Pepper, and NEC.

CAREER HIGHLIGHT

OCT 2004

Commissioned by the **Hashemite Kingdom of Jordan** to build a new website for the Jordan Tourism Board North America. The website was the vehicle for a major push by the Kingdom of Jordan to promote the country to American tourists. Website was personally unveiled by King Abdullah II at an international tourism conference, and was a huge success for the Board. Invited to Jordan for a VIP tour of the country, including a visit to the Royal Palace, upon launch of the site.

EDUCATION

1987 - 1990 **Texas Christian University**

Music Education